<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="menu">Main Menu</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome To \n Avalon Narrator</string>
    <string name="setup">Choose Roles</string>
    <string name="done_reading">Read Instructions</string>
    <string name="game_directions">How to Play</string>
    <string name="next">Continue</string>
    <string name="listen">Please Listen</string>
    <string name="change_setup">Change Roles</string>
    <string name="same_setup">Play Again</string>
    <string name="directions">Game Directions</string>
    <string name="skip">Go To Game Setup</string>
    <string name="BeginnerOptions">Character Explanations</string>
    <string name="minus">-</string>
    <string name="plus">+</string>
    <string name="in_game">Included</string>
    <string name="not_in_game">Omitted</string>
    <string name="merlinLabel">Merlin</string>
    <string name="percivalLabel">Percival</string>
    <string name="mordredLabel">Mordred</string>
    <string name="morganaLabel">Morgana</string>
    <string name="oberonLabel">Oberon</string>
    <string name="assassinLabel">Assassin</string>
    <string name="lancelot1Label">Lancelot (Rule 1)</string>
    <string name="lancelot2Label">Lancelot (Rule 2)</string>
    <string name="pauseValue">Pause Time</string>
    <string name="lancelots">Lancelot</string>
    <string name="showMore">Tell Me More</string>
    <string name="showLess">Ok I\'m Good</string>
    <string name="merlinRules">Merlin is one of the good team\'s greatest assets.  Before the game begins, Merlin gets to see the bad guys
        (with the exception of Mordred if he is in play).  This allows him to steer the good team in the right direction.  Whether it be through
        casual conversational hints, the missions he picks, or the way he votes, Merlin can help secure victory for the loyal servants of Arthur.
        He must be careful however, if the good team wins the game, the bad team has one chance to guess who Merlin is; if they guess correctly,
        the bad team wins the game.  A skillful Merlin can help his team while remaining undetected.  Merlin gives an advantage to the good (blue) team.</string>
    <string name="percivalRules">Percival is also a powerful asset for the good team.  During the game setup, Percival learns the identity of Merlin
        (unless Morgana is in play, in which case he sees two people; one is Merlin and the other is Morgana).  This gives him a considerable
        advantage in discerning who the bad guys are.  By listening to Merlin\'s hints, he can help the good team succeed missions.  In addition,
        Percival can pose himself as Merlin, and draw attention away from him.  This can be vital in the end-game phase when the bad guys attempt to
        guess who Merlin is; if they guess incorrectly, the good guys still win.  Be wary in games that include Morgana.  Morgana knows who the bad
        guys are, so she can provide just as good information as Merlin, however she may just as easily lead you astray.  Figuring out who is the
        real Merlin must be done with care to play a successful Percival. Percival gives an advantage to the good (blue) team.</string>
    <string name="assassinRules">Assassin is the direct counter to Merlin, and should be used in every game that includes Merlin.  As mentioned in the
        Merlin explanation, if the good team wins with Merlin and Assassin in play, the Assassin is allowed to guess who Merlin is.  If the Assassin\'s guess
        is correct, the bad team wins the game.  More often than not, Assassin is an assumed role, so the card need not be played.  The bad team is
        essentially a group assassin and can discuss amongst each other who they believe is Merlin before making their final decision.  In order to avoid
        confusion as to who the Assassin is guessing, it is advised that they flip over the card of the person they are guessing to indicate that a choice
        has been made.  Assasin is a must have in any game that includes Merlin, and gives an advantage to the bad (red) team.</string>
    <string name="mordredRules">Mordred is the only bad person in the game that Merlin does not get to see.  This makes him a very powerful sleeper
        agent for the bad team.  By acting as a servant of Arthur, Mordred can infiltrate missions that even Merlin thinks are good.  This can be
        vital in failing enough missions for the bad team to win the game.  Carefully planning who you pick on missions and how you go about voting
        is the most important step in maintaining your cover when playing Mordred.  Mordred gives an advantage to the bad (red) team.</string>
    <string name="morganaRules">Morgana, as was mentioned before, is the bad person who is seen as Merlin to Percival.  This gives her two ways to
        help the evil team win.  The first way is to convince Percival that she is in fact Merlin; this allows her to feed Percival bad information,
        and makes it likely that Percival will include her on missions.  The other way Morgana can win the game is to figure out who Merlin is.  By
        reading Percival\'s reactions to happenings in the game, Morgana can figure out the other person that Percival thinks may or may not be
        Merlin.  This will allow her to make an educated guess about Merlin when the game is over. Morgana gives an advantage to the bad (red) team.</string>
    <string name="oberonRules">Oberon is an agent of evil, but his presence hurts the minions of Mordred.  Oberon is not seen by his fellow minions,
        nor does he see who they are.  Oberon wins and loses with the bad team, but since he does not know who they are, he can have trouble working
        with them.  Merlin does see who Oberon is, so his affiliations may be known to the good team.  Oberon must try to find out who his teammates
        are if he wants to win the game, but he must keep in mind that doing so might out them to the good team.  Oberon is a tricky character
        to categorize, but in general, he gives an advantage to the good (blue) team.</string>
    <string name="lancelotRules">Lancelot is an expansion to Avalon, and there are two main ways he can be played.  Both sets of rules regarding
        Lancelot involve two cards, a good Lancelot and an evil Lancelot.  In the first playstyle, a deck of 7 cards is made before the game begins.
        5 cards read "no change" while the other 2 read "change".  During the step where the minions of Mordred open their eyes, Evil Lancelot does
        not open his eyes, but he does put a thumb up.  This lets the other bad guys know who he is, but their identities remain unknown to him.  At
        the beginning of each mission-choosing stage, a card is drawn from the deck, and shown to the group.  If it reads "change" the two Lancelots
        switch teams, if it reads "no change", nothing happens.  Both Lancelots must act with caution, as they may or may not change teams at any
        point during the game, and even after switching once, it is possible that they switch again.  In the second playstyle, the two Lancelots
        see each other during the pre-game setup, allowing for some play between the two.  In both cases, Merlin sees the Evil Lancelot as bad, but
        does not know which one he is.  Lancelot does not provide either team with an adcantage as far as we know.</string>
    <string name="BeginnerLabel">Gameplay</string>
    <string name="votingRules">At the beginning of each stage of the game, the player with the crown token must pick the required number of players
        to go on a mission.  A period for discussion of the proposed mission follows for as long as the "king" allows.  At this point, each player
        decides upon a vote (approve or disapprove), and extends their choice face down in front of them.  Then all players reveal their votes;
        if there is a majority of approve votes, the mission lineup is set.  If not, the mission counter token is shifted the right, and the crown
        is passed to the left.  If the mission counter token reaches 5, and the voted upon mission does not get approved, the bad team wins the
        game.</string>
    <string name="missionRules">When a mission is approved, the players on the mission are each given a success card and a fail card.  If the player
        is on the good team, they MUST put a succeed card in.  If they are on the bad team, they can choose to put in a succeed card, or a fail
        card.  All players put their choice face down in a pile, which is then shuffled and revealed.  If there one or more fail cards is revealed,
        the mission fails, and the bad team gets a point on the board.  If all cards read success, the mission passes, and the good team gets the
        point.</string>
    <string name="ladyRules">Lady of the Lake is a token who is given to the player to the right of the player with the crown.  As the crown token
        is passed along, the Lady is as well.  Immediately after the 2nd, 3rd, and 4th missions have been completed, the player with the Lady may
        choose a target player.  The target player is given the two loyalty cards (one red and one blue).  The player must hand the card that
        corresponds to their team\'s alliance back to the player with the Lady.  The holder of the Lady of the Lake therefore learns the team that
        the target player is on, and may choose to share that information to the rest of the players in the game.  However, the card that the target
        handed to the owner of the Lady must not be shown to anyone else.  Do you trust the player with the Lady?</string>
    <string name="excaliburRules">Excalibur is another card given to the crown holder during the team building phase.  The Excalibur card is then
        assigned to one of the players chosen to be on the team (but cannot be the crown holder).  When a mission is approved, and mission cards are
        decided upon the player with Excalibur may choose to use it on one other player who was on the mission.  If they chose to do so, the chosen
        player must take back their mission card and put in the other card (thus changing a success to a fail, or a fail to a success).  Excalibur
        is a great responsibility, and must be used carefully for the servants of Arthur to win the game.</string>
    <string name="BeginnerOptional">Optional Add-Ins</string>
    <string name="votingLabel">Voting</string>
    <string name="missionLabel">Missions</string>
    <string name="ladyLabel">Lady Of The Lake</string>
    <string name="excaliburLabel">Excalibur</string>


    <string name="app_name">Avalon Narrator</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_game__setup">Game_Setup</string>
    <string name="title_activity_directions">Directions</string>
    <string name="title_activity_reading">Reading</string>
    <string name="title_activity_beginner__options">Beginner_Options</string>
    <string name="voice_choice">Option One</string>

    <!-- -->

</resources>
